For passion. For honor. For destiny. For victory. For love.
Troy is a war, action, history film directed by Wolfgang Petersen.
In year 1250 B.C.
during the late Bronze age, two emerging nations begin to clash.
Paris, the Trojan prince, convinces Helen, Queen of Sparta, to leave
her husband Menelaus, and sail with him back to Troy.
After Menelaus finds out that his wife was taken by the Trojans, he
asks his brother Agamemnon to help him get her back.
Agamemnon sees this as an opportunity for power.
They set off with 1,000 ships holding 50,000 Greeks to Troy.
Achilles, played by Brad Pitt.
Paris, played by Orlando Bloom.
Hector, played by Eric Bana.
King Agamemnon, played by Brian Cox.
Odysseus, played by Sean Bean.
Menelaos, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Troy is a 2004 epic historical action film directed by
Wolfgang Petersen and written by David Benioff.
Produced by units in Malta, Mexico and Britain's Shepperton Studios, the film features an ensemble cast led by Brad Pitt,
Eric Bana, Sean Bean, Diane Kruger, Brian Cox, Brendan Gleeson, Rose Byrne, Saffron Burrows and Orlando Bloom.
It is loosely based on Homer's Iliad in its narration of the entire story of the decade-long Trojan War—condensed into little
more than a couple of weeks, rather than just the quarrel between Achilles and Agamemnon in the ninth year.
Achilles leads his Myrmidons along with the rest of the Greek army invading
the historical city of Troy, defended by Hector's Trojan army.
The end of the film (the sack of Troy) is not taken from the Iliad, but rather from Quintus
Smyrnaeus's Posthomerica, as the Iliad concludes with Hector's death and funeral.
Troy made over $497 million worldwide, making it the 60th highest-grossing film
at the time of its release and Petersen's highest-grossing film.
However, it received mixed reviews, with critics praising its entertainment value and the performances
of Pitt and Bana  while criticizing its story, which was deemed unfaithful to the Iliad.
It received a nomination for Best Costume Design at the 77th Academy
Awards and was the eighth highest-grossing film of 2004.
The film explores themes of adultery, sibling
relationship, hostility, bravery, mythology.